# **Cristian Soare**

kitcort@outlook.com | www.csoare.dev +44 7960777466

# **Professional Summary**

An experienced and highly motivated frontend developer with a strong passion for learning and building websites that provide a great user experience. I am confident about managing a busy workload and I have the ability to use my own initiative and work well under pressure, combining the hard work with dedication and professionalism. I am a very meticulous and organised person, paying great attention to details, making a significant contribution to the business.

### Education

**2018 – 2020:** A levels (Chemistry, Mathematics, Biology and Physics) at Bluecoat Sixth Form; (A, A\*, A, A respectively);

# Experience

#### Freelance

Dec 2021 – Current Frontend Software Engineer

- Engineered scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO friendly websites for multiple clients using HTML5, CSS3 + BEM, JavaScript ES6+;
- Communicated business requirements with clients and delivered high quality solutions;
- Connected to backend API s through CRUD HTTP requests;

#### **Self Employed**

Dec 2021 – Current Programming Tutor

- Tutored clients in HTML, CSS, Flexbox and JavaScript best practises;
- Simplified difficult programming concepts including responsive website development, CSS layout and API requests;
- Taught debugging best practises using Firefox inspect element tooling;
- Provided website UI designs to 1:1 and reviewed code through weekly code reviews;

#### **Employed**

Sep 2021 – Jan 2022

Customer Service Personal Tax Consultant for Her Majesty's Revenue and Customs

- Took inbound calls and dealt with tax related technical customer queries;
- Provided excellent customer service and represented Her Majesty's Government appropriately and professionally;
- Explained complex technical tax issues to customers with no tax knowledge or background appropriately;

# **Commercial Projects**

# **E-Portfolio**

https://ffportfolio.netlify.app/

- Designed, developed and hosted my client's e-portfolio using semantic HTML5 and CSS3 (BEM) best practises;
- Provided support for search engine optimisation for higher indexing through Google's search engine crawler;
- Included responsive and multi-platform support to enable the portfolio to be viewed on any platform and device;

English and Romanian, fully fluent;

Technical Skills
Proficient: HTML5, CSS3 (BEM), JavaScript ES6+, Python, Git, GitHub, cURL, Adobe Photoshop npm;
Familiar: Python Selenium, React (+hooks), Linux, SASS;
References
Available upon request.
Languages